Inventory of the Henry M. Wriston Collection, 1916 - 1972
Henry M. Wriston Collection, 1916 - 1972
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wriston, Henry Merritt, 1889-
2007-10
5.75
12
Henry Merritt Wriston (1889-1978) was a 1911 graduate of Wesleyan University and served as president of Lawrence College and Brown University. He was also active in United States foreign policy issues.
The Henry M. Wriston Collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, publications, reprints, and speeches. Topics include higher education, university administration, United States politics, and foreign relations. Many of the speeches were delivered at Brown University. The Addition of June 2008 includes materials digitized for a website project.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Majority of collection transferred from Lawrence University in 2007. These materials consist of copies from the original papers housed at Brown University, donated by Theodore Crane. The Reminiscences are photocopies donated by Theodore Crane in 1971. Originals are housed at Brown University. The Interview was acquired in 1968.
Addition of June 2008 (Acc. 2008-14) given by Mariah Klaneski, June 2008.
Biographical Note
Henry Merritt Wriston was born on July 4, 1889 in Laramie, Wyoming, and grew up in Springfield, Massachusetts. Wriston graduated from Wesleyan University with a bachelor's degree in 1911, a master's degree in 1912, and then earned his Ph.D. at Harvard University. After serving as an instructor and then full professor of history at Wesleyan from 1914 to 1925, he was appointed president of Lawrence College (now University) in Appleton, Wisconsin. At the age of 35, Wriston was reported to be the youngest college president in the country.
In 1937, Wriston became president of Brown University. He made major changes to the curriculum and the faculty, encouraging students to do their own research and drop in on classes in which they were interested. The changes prompted John D. Rockefeller, Jr., to donate $4 million in 1955 in recognition of Wriston's accomplishments.
In 1954, John Foster Dulles appointed Wriston to a committee to improve the efficiency of the diplomatic corps. Wriston continued to be involved in politics and public issues following his departure from Brown in 1955. In 1960, President Eisenhower appointed him as chairman of the Presidential Commission on Nation Goals. He also served in various capacities with the American Assembly, the World Peace Foundation, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the Council on Foreign Relations, and the New York Stock Exchange.
Wriston died on March 8, 1978. His first wife, Ruth Colton Bigelow, preceded him in death. Wriston was survived by his second wife, Marguerite Woodworth, whom he married in 1947. Wriston was also survived by two children, Walter B. Wriston and Barbara Wriston.
Collection Overview
The Henry M. Wriston Collection consists of biographical material, correspondence, publications, reprints, and speeches. Topics include higher education, university administration, United States politics, and foreign relations. Many of the speeches were delivered at Brown University.
Materials in the Addition of June 2008 (Acc. 2008-14) were used in creating the website http://www.henrymerrittwriston.org/. They include materials from other repositories and the Wriston family, as well as photographs and audio recordings.
Collection Arrangement
Within each series, materials are arranged chronologically.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wriston, Henry Merritt, 1889-; Lawrence College (Appleton, Wis.); Brown University.; Universities and colleges--United States.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Politics and government--20th century.; Education--Aims and objectives.; Education, Higher.; College presidents--United States--Biography.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.
Related Material
Vertical File, Wesleyan University Archives
Henry Wriston Papers, Brown University
Henry Wriston Collection, Lawrence University
Henry Merritt Wriston website: http://www.henrymerrittwriston.org
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Biography
  - Installation of Dr. Wriston, Brown Alumni Monthly, v.37:6. January 1937 (Box 1)
  - A New President Comes to Brown, Brown Alumni Monthly, v. 37.7. February 1937
  - Colby and Rockefeller Opinions. 1937-1943
  - Liberal Policy Marks Wriston’s First Year, BDH. February 3, 1938
  - Guest Speaker at Amherst, Amherst Alumni Council News, v. 13:1. October 1939
  - The Merritt System, Sir Brown. October 1941
  - Crusader From the Campus, Newsweek, v.18:p.68. November 24, 1941
  - Not a Candidate, Brown Alumni Monthly, v.42:6. January 1942
  - Brown University is Guided by a Firm but Liberal Hand, Christian Science Monitor. May 4, 1942
  - Dr. Henry M Writson by Richard L. Stokes, St. Louis Post-Dispatch. August 1942
  - Andrews and Wriston, Presidents of Brown, Pawtucket, RI Paper. July 1943
  - What of Brown? Providence Journal. January 14, 1945
  - After Ten Years as Brown’s Leader, Brown Alumni Monthly v. 47:6. March-April 1947
  - Birthday Cake, Brown Alumni Monthly v. 47:6. March-April 1947
  - Dutcher, George Matthew. An Historical and Critical Survey of Wesleyan University and Related Subjects pp39-40. 1948
  - Dr. Wriston is First Individual to Head Universities Association, Providence Journal. November 28, 1948
  - Wriston Chosen to Head AAU, Brown Daily Herald. November 30, 1948
  - Typical Two Week Period, by Jerry Berkelhammer, Brown Daily Herald. February 19, 1951
  - Wriston Will Tour Europe, Brown Daily Herald. March 1, 1951.
  - Island Laboratory for Basic Ideas, by Clifford C. Nelson, New York Times Magazine. May 21, 1951
  - Wriston of Brown, by Selig Greenberg, Providence Journal Company. July 1951
  - An Ideal Choice for the Post, Brown Alumni Monthly v. 54:6. March 1954
  - A Man of No Ordinary Stature Prepares to Retire, Providence Journal. March 31, 1955
  - Wriston Will Discuss Foreign Service on Nationwide Tour. March 8, 1955
  - Tribute to Henry Merrit Wriston, Pembroke Record. May 13, 1955
  - To Be a Witness/ The Heralds Tribute, Brown Alumni Monthly. May 1955
  - Wriston to Direct American Assembly, Brown Alumni Monthly. October 1955
  - Wriston to Direct Educational Group, Brown Daily Herald. September 20, 1955
  - 400 Pay Homage to Wriston at Testimonial, Brown Daily Herald. September 23, 1955
  - Wriston Speaking by Ruth E. Sandborn, Brown Alumni Monthly v. 56:2. November 1955
  - A Man of no Ordinary Stature by George Banta, JR., Rainbow of Delta Tau Delta. December 1955
  - Honors at Home: A Moving Valedictory for Dr. and Mrs. Wriston, Brown Alumni Monthly. January 1956
  - Death of Griswold Touches Off Talent Hunt for New Yale Head, New York Times, Sunday. May 5, 1963
  - End of a Notable Presidential Term, Brown Alumni Monthly. March 1964
  - Life With Henry by John K. McIntyre ’39, Brown Alumni Monthly. May 1965
- Correspondence
  - Newhall, Richard A. May 1, 1916
  - Preble, Mrs. I. W. June 14, 1937
  - Barden, Graham A. (House). May 25, 1949
  - Honorary Degree 1950-1963
  - Materials Collected for Brown History, Particularly on H.M. Wriston 1911-1966
- Publications
  - List, 1937-1955
  - List, 1955-1962
  - Forerunners of Colonel House and John Lind. New York Times, v. 65, p.2. March 6, 1916
  - Presidential Special Agents in Diplomacy. American Political Science Review, v. 10, pp. 481-499. August 1916
  - President Wilson's Mexican Policy. Springfield Republican. October 13, 1916
  - Are Alliances Un-American. New York Times. March 11, 1917, p II, 2:7
  - The Church and the Nation. Zion's Herald v. 95, pp 640-941. May 9, 1917/ Patriotic Rally: The Penny Press. May 10, 1917
  - Review of Hackett's Ireland. Historical Outlook, v. 10, p266. May 1919
  - Review of Muhlon's The Vandal of Europe. The Historical Outlook, v. 10, p268. May 1919
  - An Archive Building at Washington. Review of Reviews, v. 70, pp. 191-192. August 1924
  - Delta Tau Delta Attains Highest Scholastic Record in Fraternity's History. The Rainbow of Delta Tau Delta LX, pp.74-75. January 1937
  - Nature of a Liberal College. Review: Brown Alumni Monthly 37:10 pp. 272-273. May 1937
  - Report of Commission on Academic Freedom and Academic Tenture. AAc Bulletin, v. 24:107. March 1938
  - Review of John B. Johnston's Scholarship and Democracy. Journal of Higher Education, v.9:403-404. October 1938
  - Perspective Upon Education. Educational Record bv.31:suppl. 13, pp 90-107. January 1940
  - College Students and the War National Policy Papers no.2. June 30, 1940
  - Academic Tenure. American Scholar v. 9:3 pp. 339-349. July 1940
  - Faith in Democracy. Pathfinder. June 21, 1941
  - For Defense Today- For Hope Tomorrow. Brown Daily Herald. October 14, 1941
  - Review of Arthur D. Howden's Mr. House of Texas. American Historical Review v. 47, pp. 166-167. October 1941
  - Denies Intention of Running for Public Office. December 2, 1941
  - Prepare for peace, Chapter III. Strategy of Peace. 1941
  - Wriston Brands Rivers and Harbors Bill as Political Pap. Brown Daily Herald. January 8, 1942
  - Review of Nicholas J. Spykman's American Strategy. American Journal of International Law. July 1942.
  - To the Men of Brown: An Open Letter. November 1, 1942
  - Review of Hans Kahn's World Order in Historical Perspective. American Historical Review v.48:4. July 1, 1943
  - Challenge to Freedom. Brown Alumni Monthly (Excerpts). 1943
  - Challenge to Freedom. Reviews: William Frankin Sands, Charles E. Noyes. 1943
  - Dr. Wriston Lauds Dewey's Stand on U.N. Brown Daily Herald. October 20, 1944
  - Strategy of Peace. Reviews: James W. Ryan- Political Science Review, F.L. Schulman- American Political Science Review, Norman Angell- SRL. 1944-1945
  - Review of James T. Shotwell's The Great Decision. American Journal of American Law v. 39. 1945
  - It will be a Triumphant Year, If… Brown Alumni Monthly v. 47:2. September-October 1946.
  - Review of Sidney Hook's Education For Modern Man. Philosophical Reviews. January 1947
  - Wriston not Interested in Atomic Energy Post. Brown Daily Herald. February 20, 1947
  - Debate With Senator Pepper. Brown Daily Herald. April 11, 1947. Harvard Crimson. April 12, 1947
  - What Good is a College Degree. American Magazine v. 143:26-27+. 1947 (Vacation Issue)
  - Dr. Wriston Condemns U.S. College Plan. Providence Evening Bulletin. January 3, 1948
  - Wriston Asserts Draft Necessary. Brown Daily Herald p.1. May 18, 1948
  - Review of James Bryant Conant's Education in a Divided World. Providence Sunday Journal. October 21, 1948.
  - Wriston Attacks System of Accrediting Schools. Brown Daily Herald. December 7, 1948
  - Sojourn Among the Bureacrats. Brunonia, v. 2:4 pp3+. April 1947
  - Wriston Sees School Crisis. Providence Evening Bulletin. September 11, 1949
  - Wriston Signs Freedom Scroll. Brown Daily Herald. October 3, 1950
  - American Institutions of Higher Learning Must be Prepared to Face Financial Storm. Brown Daily Herald. November 6, 1950
  - Wriston Favors Conant Plan for Draft. Brown Daily Herald. November 17, 1950
  - UMT Controversies Discussed by Wriston and Carmichael. Brown Daily Herald. November 28, 1950
  - Crisis Committee Statement. Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. December 12, 1950
  - Washington Was Right (Editorial). Hartford Times. November 8, 1951
  - Review of Merlo J. Pusey's Charles Evans Hughes. Saturday Review of Literature pp. 15-16. December 15, 1951
  - Finance Higher Education. Brown Alumni Monthly v. 52:3. January 1952
  - President Wriston Favors Eisenhower in Presidential Race. Brown Daily Herald. February 6, 1952
  - Dr. Wriston Comments on Contemporary Education. Brown Daily Herald. Interview by Robert F. Hewes. May 29, 1953
  - Harvard President Nominee Given Start by Dr. Wriston. Evening Bulletin Providence. June 5, 1953
  - Dr. Wriston Sees Soviet Likely to Modify Policy. Brown Daily Herald (by Selig Greenberg). After June 1953
  - Wriston Declares Retirement. Brown Daily Herald. September 17, 1953
  - Review of A. Whitney Griswold's Essays on Education. Yale Review. Fall 1954
  - Young Men and the Foreign Service. Reprint From Foreign Affairs. June 15, 1954
  - Wriston: Builder of Schools, Lily Ponds and Mentality. Brown Daily Herald. November 5, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Optimism Manifest in Terms of the Present. Brown Daily Herald. May 7, 1955
  - Review of P.A. Reynol's British Foreign Policy in the Inter-War Years. Annals of the American Academy of Political and Society Science. July 1955
  - Review of Russell Kirk's Academic Freedom. Yale Review. Summer 1955
  - The Secretary of State Abroad. Foreign Affairs v. 34:523-40. July 1956
  - Education and the National Interest. Foreign Affairs v35 pp.564-80. July 1957
  - Wriston Speaking Review by Marylynn Monk Boris '52 (Pembroke). Pembroke Alumna. January 1958
  - Diplomacy in a Democracy Review by W.C. Olson. World Politics 10: 318-325. January 1958
  - Wriston Asserts- Vigilance Committee Interview. Brown Daily Herald. February 20, 1959
  - Humanists and Generalists. Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science: 325. September 1959
  - The Special Envoy. Foreign Affairs 30. January 1960
  - The Futility of Accrediting. Journal of Higher Education: 31. June 1960
  - The Individual. Goals for Americans p. 35-58. November 27, 1960
  - The Importance of Goals. General Electric Defence Quarterly v.4:1. January-March 1961
  - Wriston Opinions Interviews. Brown Daily Herald. March 2, 3, 6, 1961
  - The Age Revolution. Foreign Affairs 39, July 1961
  - Thoughts for Tomorrow. Foreign Affairs 40. April 1962
  - Goal for Young American Parent-Teachers. Association Magazine 56. May 1962
  - Review of Harold W. Dodd's The Academic President. Journal of Higher Education. June 1962
  - Condemnation of the Status Quo. Wisconsin Education Association. May 1963
  - Dr. Wriston's Academy Views (Editorial). Providence Sunday Journal. June 16, 1963
  - Publish or Perish. Saturday Review p.59. July 17, 1965
  - Taking the National Pulse. Saturday Review p.25-29. September 11, 1965
  - The Selection of Presidents. Wesleyan University Alumnus v. 50:4. May 1966
  - The Brave New World. Res Publica v. 1:2. May 1966
  - Letter to Editor. New York Times. December 3, 1972
- Reprints
  - List, 1955-1962
- Speeches
  - List, 1937-1955
  - List, 1955-1962
  - Why You Should Vote for Mr. Hughes at 20th Century Club, Middleton. (No text). Article: Penny Press, October 24, 1916 p.5
  - The Issues of the Campaign Republican Rally, Middleton. Article: Penny Press, November 4, 1916 p.1
  - Municipal Ownership of Street Railways. Article: Penny Press, May 24, 1917, p.10
  - The Crisis of the War. Article: Penny Press, March 1, 1918 p.10
  - The College Man As a Citizen. Wesleyan University, Freshman Fundamental Course, May 22, 1918
  - Integrity of Teaching. Educational Week Address, Meriden, Connecticut. December 9, 1921
  - Clubs and Lodges. Middletown Press, January 10, 1923 p.10
  - American Foreign Relations and the Party System. League of Women Voters, West Hartford, Connecticut. October 3, 1924
  - Wesleyan College History Freeman Fundamentals. Article: Wesleyan Argus, October 23, 1924 p.1
  - The American Foreign Service Middletown Teachers' Association, Memorial Chapel. October 28, 1924
  - Treaty of Lausanne, Middletown Teachers Association. Article: Evening Press, December 10, 1924
  - Relative Emphasis in Instruction in International Law, Conference of Teachers of International Law. April 22, 1925
  - Art is More Than Logic but Less Than Faith Convocation. February 4, 1937
  - Installation Address, Sayles Hall. February 3, 1937
  - Past and Present, Pembroke Convocation. February 5, 1937
  - Brown Alumni Address, Brown Club dinner, N.Y. February 15, 1937
  - Brown Alumni Advisory Council. February 21, 1937
  - The Education of George Washington 1st Light Infantry Dinner, Providence. Freshman-Sophomore Chapel, Brown. February 21, 1937. February 29, 1939
  - College Foundations for Adult Learning. Phi Beta Kappa Dinner, Providence. February 24, 1937
  - The Temper of the Modern College, Providence Chamber of Commerce. March 4, 1937
  - Wholesale Or Retail, Churchmen's Dinner, YMCA, Providence. March 9, 1937
  - Blind Spots, Rhode Island Secondary School Principals Association, Providence. (Also Language Leaflet No2-Washington, D.C. 1939) March 10, 1937
  - Defensive Mood, Wesleyan Alumni Dinner, Boston. April 2, 1937
  - Why is it so Hard? Convocation-Brown. April 8, 1937
  - Common Mission of Church and College, Churchmen's Dinner, Providence. April 20, 1937
  - The Major Premise, Pembroke Convocation. April 20, 1937
  - Fraternities, Interfraternity Governing Board Banquet. April 28, 1937
  - Spring Day, Brown Convocation. May, 1937
  - Whither Education. Rhode Island Institute of Instruction, Providence. October 28, 1937
  - Whosoever Shall Seek to Save His Life Shall Lose it. Convocation- Wesleyan University. November 7, 1937
  - Thanksgiving Dinner That Was Never Eaten. Honors Award, Brown University. November 23, 1937
  - Education and Patriotism. Society of Colonial Dames, Providence. November 15, 1937
  - Library As an Obstacle to Education. Tavern Club, Boston. December 2, 1937
  - Will the College Disappear? New England Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, Boston. December 3, 1937
  - Books to Memorize. Pembroke Chapel. December 7, 1937
  - Some Matters of Current Interest. Faculty Club, Providence. December 16, 1937
  - College Parable. Brown Chapel. January 4, 1938
  - Dedication of School of Design Metcalf Bldg. June 9, 1937
  - Richness in Life. Class Day- Brown. June 18, 1937
  - Back to the Blanket. Ivy Day-Pembroke. June 18, 1937
  - Class of 1897 Reunion Dinner, Brown. June 19, 1937
  - Alumni Meeting, Brown. June 21, 1937
  - Education or Training. Society for Promotion of Engineering Education, Boston. July 1, 1937
  - Freshman Welcome Sayles. September 16, 1937
  - The Constitution. Convocation- Brown. September 2, 1937
  - Academic Freedom and Tenure. Association of American Colleges, Vassar College, N.Y. October 22, 1937
  - Graduate Record Exam. February 10, 1938
  - Alumni Advisory Council. Brown Alumni Monthly v. 38:3. February 12, 1938
  - State of Brown University. Brown Club, N.Y. February 16, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Fight the Good Fight. Phi Beta Kappa, Providence. March 2, 1938
  - Christian Philosophy of Life. Student Christian Movement, Northfield. March 4, 1938
  - Higher Education in a Democracy: The Function of the Privately Endowed College. March 10, 1938
  - High School Senior and the Universities. Radio- Columbia Broadcast, Boston. March 12, 1938
  - Churches and Education. First Baptist Church, Providence. April 28, 1938.
  - Delta Phi Banquet. Nyatt, Rhode Island. May 7, 1938
  - Distraction or Fulfillment. Brown Christian Association, Providence. May 12, 1938
  - Self Pity. Class Day, Brown. June 17, 1938
  - Alumni, Brown Alumni Monthly. June 30, 1938
  - In Quietness and in Confidence. Convocation- Sayles. September 28, 1938
  - Man or Machine. American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Providence. October 5, 1938. Article: American Society of Mechanical Engineers, November 1938
  - Alumni Day Dinner, Brown Alumni Monthly. October 7, 1938
  - Christmas. University Club, Providence. December 19, 1938
  - Science and its Limitations. Metcalf Chemical Research Lab. December 28, 1938
  - Welcome. Archaeological Institute and Philological Association, Providence. December 28, 1938.
  - How to Make Democracy Work. Junior-Senior Chapel. January 5, 1939
  - Alumni and Their Function. Alumni Advisory Council. February 11, 1939
  - Education of Abraham Lincoln. Pembroke Chapel. February 14, 1939
  - Alumni Speech, Brown Club, Washington. February 23, 1939
  - Sigma Xi Dinner, Brown, Providence. March 18, 1939
  - College and University Libraries. Chapter From: The Library of Tomorrow, Ala Chi. April 1939
  - Liberal Learning. Duke Centennial Celebration. April 21, 1939
  - E ducation for the Defense of Democracy. A.K.A. Education and Democracy. Academy of Political Science, N.Y. May 3, 1939
  - Responsibility Spring May, Brown. May 11, 1939
  - General Record Examination Freshman and Sophomore Chapel. May 16, 1939
  - Issues May 16, 1939
  - University Policies Cammarian Club Annual Dinner, Faunce House. May 26, 1939
  - Shall We Go To War. Convocation, Sayles Hall. September 27, 1934
  - Brown University 1939, Alumni Dinner, Crescent Park. October 6, 1939
  - Social Significance of Science. Natural Academy of Science, Providence. Scientific Monthly 50, p 264-66. October 23, 1939
  - Perfect Peace, Convocation, Wesleyan University. November 12, 1939
  - Foreign Language. New England Foreign Language Association, Rhode Island Group, Faunce House. November 25, 1939
  - War and Education. Brown Alumnae Club, N.Y. January 31, 1940
  - Debunked Too Much. New York Brown Club. February 5, 1940
  - Brown University's Public Relations. Brown Alumni Monthly v40:7 pp.175-76. March 1940
  - Reform of Education. Phi Beta Kappa Dinner, Providence. March 4, 1940
  - Lenten Discussion. Faunce House, Brown. March 20, 1940
  - American Policy: Positive or Negative. Academy of Political Science, New York. April 11, 1940
  - Problems of Higher Education. University Club, Providence. April 22, 1940
  - Students and the War. Freshman-Sophomore Chapel. January 16, 1940
  - Peace As a Flight From Reality. April 23, 1940
  - Educational World: Pan American Scientific Congress. American Council for Adult Education, Brown Alumni Monthly. May 13, 1940
  - Cultural Self Reliance and the Democratic Process. Association Alumni Meeting, Brown Alumni Monthly (Sept. 1940). June 17, 1940
  - Are We Going to War. Convocation, Brown. September 25, 1940
  - Tomorrow At Brown. Alumni Day Dinner, Brown Alumni Monthly v 51:4 (Nov. 1940). October 11, 1940
  - Symposium on Student Appraisal. Carnegie Foundation, Lake Mohonk. October 14, 1940
  - Third Term. NBC, Providence (WEAN). October 21, 1940
  - In the World Ye Shall Have Tribulations. Junior-Senior Chapel, Brown. October 24, 1940
  - Personal Powers of the President. NBC, Providence (WEAN). October 29, 1940
  - Military and Moral Initiative. National Interfraternity Conference Dinner, New York. November 29, 1940
  - Discussion of S.C. Pepper's Article 'Universities Discover Art.' Informal Conference on the Arts, Carnegie Corporation. December 17, 1940
  - Higher Education: A Rhode Island Asset. Chamber of Commerce, Providence. December 19, 1940
  - Reality of Education. Freshman-Sophomore Chapel. February 14, 1941
  - Preparing for Peace. New England Council, Providence. March 14, 1941
  - Good or Bad College. Convocation, Dedication of Fraternity Quad, Lawrence College, Appleton. March 22, 1941
  - Universities and the Crisis. International Student Service, New Haven. April 5, 1941
  - After the War-What? April 15, 1941
  - American Commitments. Peace Week, Brown. April 24, 1941
  - Design in America. Lord and Taylor Design Award Luncheon, New York. April 29, 1941
  - United States Naval Academy. Freshman-Sophomore Chapel. May 6, 1941
  - Simplicity and Time Factor. New England Modern Language Association, Providence. May 9, 1941
  - National Unity. Under the Elms, Brown. June 13, 1941
  - Postulate for Educational Reform. Associated Alumni, Providence Sayles. June 16, 1941
  - Citizens Emergency Committee. Farm and Home Hour, NBC, New York. July 19, 1941
  - Outlooks and Insights. Friends of Libraries Luncheon, American Library Association, Boston. June 23, 1941
  - We Must Have Priorities in Spending. Citizens Emergency Committee Radio Address, Congressional Record. July 19, 1941 (Box 4)